<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on vitvar.com</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on vitvar.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</webMaster>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 10:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fresh New Website</title>
      <link>/2019/06/fresh-new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2019/06/fresh-new-website/</guid>
      <description>I finally refurbished my website to a new content and style. I am now using Hugo and a template from serialized.net which I very much like for its simplicity (thank you Josh Barratt). I am also using GitHub to store the source code and GitHub pages to host the website. There is two docker containers (Hugo and nginx server) that I use to run my website locally before I post the final content to GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Outbound Call and DNS Resolver Timeout</title>
      <link>/2019/05/service-call-resolver-timeout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2019/05/service-call-resolver-timeout/</guid>
      <description>In order to maintain your integration platform&amp;rsquo;s resilience, you should have timeouts on your services&amp;rsquo; outbound calls. When you do, any long running outbound service call won&amp;rsquo;t block your threads. And it is important to have enough threads in your thread pool at any point in time as otherwise your integration middleware may be blocked and process no requests.
You should be able to set two kinds of timeouts on your outbound HTTP service calls, namely HTTP connect timeout and HTTP read timeout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Namespaces Declarations Overhead</title>
      <link>/2019/04/xml-ns-declarations-overhead/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2019/04/xml-ns-declarations-overhead/</guid>
      <description>When I checked some of request or response messages of SOA services, I noticed that there are sometimes multiple declarations of the same namespaces on several elements in the response message&amp;rsquo;s XML tree. This can make the message pretty big, sometimes by almost 30%. May be you do not need to bother as your messages are not big, however, there are SOA deployments where this can be an issue, for example, messages may include empty elements and it is not possible to optimise them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SFTP probe with no PID</title>
      <link>/2019/03/sftp-probe-no-pid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2019/03/sftp-probe-no-pid/</guid>
      <description>There is no ideal world where all integrations use HTTP protocol. HTTP alone that SOAP services use (or even better REST) bring many advantages across the stack. Having said that, there are cases when a certain integration uses other protocols, for example, SFTP to upload a file to a remote server. And there is Enterprise Service Bus that acts as a message broker mixing and matching various protocols that your enterprise integration requires.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weblogic DMS Metric Collector</title>
      <link>/2019/01/weblogic-dms-metric-collector/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2019/01/weblogic-dms-metric-collector/</guid>
      <description>I often need to evaluate performance of Weblogic apps, components and services and I use Weblogic Dynamic Monitoring Service that provides a massive amount of sensors. You can access DMS in a number of ways, such as Weblogic Scripting Tool (WLST), Java API or DMS Spy application. As it was a cumbersome process to always craft a Java program to retrieve a metric from DMS, I thought it would be much easier to retrieve metrics directly via DMS Spy app by using a command line utility just by saying which metrics from which DMS table you need.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent Web Services Meet Social Computing</title>
      <link>/2012/03/intelligent-services-social-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2012/03/intelligent-services-social-computing/</guid>
      <description>I was glad to co-chair AAAI Spring Symposium on Intelligent Web Services Meet Social Computing that was held in Stanford from 26-28 March 2012. This post summarises the symposium goals, topics and program.
Goals Web services have become a core feature that developers expect from any Web application. A leading service and mashup directory ProgrammableWeb reports that the number of Web services has been steadily increasing since 2008. In spite of this increase several problems are starting to surface; design quality tend to suffer from common mistakes, development cost is normally high due to lack of collaboration and reuse, integration with other services is difficult because of lack of semantic service descriptions, sharing with other developers and users is not well supported, and the social requirements to boost endorsement by the community are not well understood or met.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD research guidelines</title>
      <link>/2011/04/research-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2011/04/research-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>This post summarises my view on how a PhD student should work in his research field and successfully complete a PhD degree. This should mainly serve my PhD students that I work with at the Czech Technical University in Prague and as such is tailored for Czech conditions, however, anyone is free to read and comment.
In summary, as a PhD student, you should follow a research methodology and produce outputs such as publications, software prototypes as well as collaborate and establish in your research community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Computing May Decrease Your API Call Limit</title>
      <link>/2011/03/cloud-computing-may-decrease-your-api-call-limit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2011/03/cloud-computing-may-decrease-your-api-call-limit/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dive Deep into REST at Second Annual Workshop</title>
      <link>/2011/01/dive-deep-into-rest-at-second-annual-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2011/01/dive-deep-into-rest-at-second-annual-workshop/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Interoperability of Clouds with DeltaCloud</title>
      <link>/2010/10/towards-interoperability-of-clouds-with-deltacloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2010/10/towards-interoperability-of-clouds-with-deltacloud/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert Tweets to Emails with Google AppsScript</title>
      <link>/2010/10/convert-tweets-to-emails-with-google-appsscript/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2010/10/convert-tweets-to-emails-with-google-appsscript/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understand Your Social Impact with BackType</title>
      <link>/2010/09/understand-your-social-impact-with-backtype/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2010 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2010/09/understand-your-social-impact-with-backtype/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web&#39;s Biggest Brands Mapped in a Fantasy Landscape</title>
      <link>/2010/09/webs-biggest-brands-mapped-in-a-fantasy-landscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2010/09/webs-biggest-brands-mapped-in-a-fantasy-landscape/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web APIs and Service Mashups Research Workshop</title>
      <link>/2010/08/web-apis-and-service-mashups-research-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2010 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2010/08/web-apis-and-service-mashups-research-workshop/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No API? Use ScraperWiki to Add One</title>
      <link>/2010/08/no-api-use-scraperwiki-to-add-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2010 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2010/08/no-api-use-scraperwiki-to-add-one/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook iPhone SDK Adds Graph API and OAuth 2.0</title>
      <link>/2010/08/facebook-iphone-sdk-adds-graph-api-and-oauth-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2010/08/facebook-iphone-sdk-adds-graph-api-and-oauth-2.0/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API Anti-Patterns: How to Avoid Common REST Mistakes</title>
      <link>/2010/08/api-anti-patterns-how-to-avoid-common-rest-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2010 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2010/08/api-anti-patterns-how-to-avoid-common-rest-mistakes/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Open Courses from Top Universities Via API</title>
      <link>/2010/08/search-open-courses-from-top-universities-via-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2010/08/search-open-courses-from-top-universities-via-api/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google APIs at Your Fingertips</title>
      <link>/2010/07/google-apis-at-your-fingertips/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2010/07/google-apis-at-your-fingertips/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Book on Semantic Technologies for E-Government</title>
      <link>/2010/03/book-semantic-technologies-egov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2010/03/book-semantic-technologies-egov/</guid>
      <description>Our book on Semantic Technologies for E-Government, co-edited by me, Vassilios Peristeras and Konstantinos Tarabanis, has finally been published by Springer Germany. It has over 30 contributing authors working on semantic technologies applied to e-government mainly as part of EU FP6 and FP7 funded projects. The book is divided into three major parts, Architectures and Process Integration, Ontologies and Interoperability, and Portals and User Interaction. It provides many interesting details on how semantic technologies can effectively solve core integration problems as well as how they can facilitate emerging e-government trends such as one-stop-shopping, cross-border e-government, or participation of citizens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor papers with a Google spreadsheet</title>
      <link>/2009/07/monitor-papers-google-spreadsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2009 15:10:10 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2009/07/monitor-papers-google-spreadsheet/</guid>
      <description>Google Scholar is a great service which you can use to monitor citations of (your) papers. The major problem I have with Google Scholar, though, is that it does not expose any metadata about papers and citations. I have thus created a simple solution that allows you to extract papers’ titles and their citation counts and expose them as atom feed. And all what you need to do this is Google Spreadsheets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Computers Chapter</title>
      <link>/2009/04/advances-in-computers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2009/04/advances-in-computers/</guid>
      <description>Elsevier published our work on Semantic Web Services with Lightweight Descriptions of Services in its Advances in Computers, volume 76 (co-authored by me, Jacek Kopecky, Jana Viskova, Adrian Mocan, Mick Kerrigan and Dieter Fensel). In order to publish in this book, authors need to receive an invitation from Elsevier and we were glad to receive such invitation in 2008. This book’s topic is about foundations and applications of Semantic Web including Social Web and Web Services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Innovative SOA B2B Solution Wins €700 Prize</title>
      <link>/2009/04/b2b-soa-solution-prize/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2009/04/b2b-soa-solution-prize/</guid>
      <description>Our solution for innovative SOA technology that we use to solve various B2B real-world scenarios wins the prize of 700€ at the industrial track of ASWC in Bangkok, Thailand. Development of the underlying technology (called WSMX) begun in early 2004 as part of DERI and STI research activities, and starting from 2006 we use this technology to solve various real-world scenarios from B2B domain defined by the Semantic Web Services (SWS) Challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google&#39;s Plans on Semantics</title>
      <link>/2009/04/google-and-semantics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2009 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2009/04/google-and-semantics/</guid>
      <description>Google’s VP research, Alfred Spector, reveals plans on exploiting huge amount of data for building a “database of concepts and relationships between them” for better search results. He envisions that Google should be able to learn such information from interactions and a very large amount of information, a different approach to a traditional AI where such an ontology is usually imposed to a system and controlled by an expert.
The use of such ontology is then pretty obvious:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exclude Self-traffic from your Website’s Access Reports</title>
      <link>/2009/01/exclude-self-traffic-from-your-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 21:13:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2009/01/exclude-self-traffic-from-your-web/</guid>
      <description>I use Google Analytics to track my website’s traffic and I do not want my own traffic to be included in the reports.
Google Analytics comes with two suggestions how to do this, however, neither of them is suitable for me. The first option is to exclude all traffic based on one or more IPs. I can set a filter to exclude a traffic from my work as well as home networks, however, this would also exclude the traffic from anyone sitting on the same network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formal Model for Semantic-Driven Service Execution</title>
      <link>/2008/12/model-sws-execution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2008/12/model-sws-execution/</guid>
      <description>Our work on formal model for semantic-driven service execution (co-authored by me, Adrian Mocan, and Maciej Zaremba) will be published in proceedings of the 7th International Semantic Web Conference (ISWC) held in Karlsruhe, Germany in November this year (acceptance rate was 16%). You can access the full paper here.
In this work we define a model and an algorithm for execution of services which interfaces we model using Abstract State Machine (ASM) using ontological concepts for their vocabularies (we call this description a choreography).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hRESTS: a Microformat for RESTful Services</title>
      <link>/2008/12/hrests-microformat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2008/12/hrests-microformat/</guid>
      <description>Our work on hRESTS, a microformat to describe RESTful services (co-authored by Jacek Kopecky, Karthik Gomadam and me) has been accepted to a Web Intelligence conference to be held in Sydney, Australia this year in December (the acceptance rate was around 18%). You can download the full paper here.
The value of today’s Web applications is no longer only in providing content to consumers but also in exposing functionality through public APIs designed for machine consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planned Book on Semantic Technologies for E-Government</title>
      <link>/2008/07/semantic-technologies-egov/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2008/07/semantic-technologies-egov/</guid>
      <description>Our proposal for a book entitled “Semantic Technologies for E-Government: An European Perspective” has been accepted by Springer and we are currently in a process of signing a contract. This is a co-edited book with three editors, namely Vassilios Peristeras (DERI, Galway, Ireland), Tomas Vitvar (STI Innsbruck, Austria) and Konstantinos Tarabanis (CERTH, Thessaloniki, Greece).
The goal of the book is to describe the current state of research and development in e-government empowered by semantic technologies, mainly as results of EU-funded research projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WSMO-Lite at ESWC 2008</title>
      <link>/2008/07/wsmo-lite-eswc-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2008/07/wsmo-lite-eswc-2008/</guid>
      <description>WSMO-Lite which describes a lightweight service ontology and annotation mechanism for Web Service Description Language (WSDL), has been accepted for the European Semantic Web Conference 2008 (you can download the paper here).
WSMO-Lite which is currently under a review process in a CMS working group, has been co-authored by Tomas Vitvar, Jacek Kopecky, Jana Viskova and Dieter Fensel. In this paper we define the service ontology describing constructs for services’ information model (ontology) as well as functional services’ descriptions (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Success of a PhD Endeavour</title>
      <link>/2008/07/success-phd-endeavour/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2008 18:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2008/07/success-phd-endeavour/</guid>
      <description>What are successful factors in completing a PhD degree? There is no ideal student who knows what he/she wants from the very beginning, however, there are several success criteria that you as a PhD student should know in order to be well prepared to work as a researcher in the future. Although a PhD degree is awarded based on a successful defence of your PhD thesis — a report on research results that you complete during studies — you should be active in a research community, publish and present papers in conferences and journals, and most importantly, do innovative work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to move on...</title>
      <link>/2008/03/time-to-move-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2008 19:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2008/03/time-to-move-on/</guid>
      <description>It has been 3 years and 4 months I have arrived to Ireland and started working with Semantic Web Services group in DERI. I was initially hired by Christoph Bussler, the co-founder of DERI Galway, and since then worked with Stefan Decker, Dieter Fensel, and Manfred Hauswirth. I contributed to many projects and initiatives including Knowledge Web, SemanticGov, Lion, WSMO, SAWSDL, etc. Ireland will always mean a special place for me and my family as this was the place where I started the family life and where my two children Tomas and Klara were born.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RESTful Services and Semantic Descriptions</title>
      <link>/2008/01/restful-services-semantic-descriptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2008 12:05:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2008/01/restful-services-semantic-descriptions/</guid>
      <description>RESTful services are usually described in a free-text form in HTML while service descriptions (i.e. service contracts) are not explicitly defined. In addition, when creating Web 2.0 applications (mashups), the problem with integration of data produced or consumed by these services is still a remaining issue. A developer must either implement a mediator or change the implementation of a service (if possible) to conform to integration needs. SA-REST introduces a novel approach to annotation of RESTful service description in a HTML using microformats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux freedom: basis for integrated home building on open source</title>
      <link>/2008/01/integrated-home-opensource/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2008 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2008/01/integrated-home-opensource/</guid>
      <description>I have recently purchased a Linksys WRTSL54GS router, and installed a third-party firmware called OpenWrt.
I am amazed as I actually got almost a fully-fledged linux running in a very small box (see for example the packages available for white russian distribution of OpenWrt). In fact, I was always thinking about having a linux server for my home network management, however, I wanted to avoid a big server (due to the power consumption, space and possibly noise).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Web Project Comes to its End...</title>
      <link>/2007/12/knowledgeweb-comes-to-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2007 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2007/12/knowledgeweb-comes-to-end/</guid>
      <description>Knowledge Web project, a four-year EU research project, comes to its end by the end of this year. The project forms the Semantic Web community in Europe while contributing to the cutting edge research and development of semantic technologies along the lines of education, research and industry. My major contributions were in semantic web services that enable automation of services&amp;rsquo; tasks. Over the past three years, I worked as a leader of these activities and, thanks to the project, we were able to make a significant contribution in the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto Mount a Network File System in Ubuntu based on a Specific Network</title>
      <link>/2007/10/automount-filesystems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2007 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2007/10/automount-filesystems/</guid>
      <description>When you use different network file systems on different networks (e.g., you often move your laptop from work to home) you may want to mount them automatically depending on the network you are connected to. You can do this with a script I introduce in this post.
I often take my laptop from work to home and thus change the networks. At work there are network file systems which I use to backup my data and share files with others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SESA: Emerging Technology for Service-Centric Environments</title>
      <link>/2007/10/sesa-service-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2007 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2007/10/sesa-service-environments/</guid>
      <description>The IEEE Software magazine published in the November/December issue our article entitled SESA: Emerging Technology for Service-Centric Environments where we discuss the innovative SOA technology based on the semantic service descriptions. We first outline a number of governing principles for the SESA design, research and implementation such as the service-oriented principle, the semantic principle, and the problem-solving principle. Following these principles, the SESA defines a set of essential functionalities (middleware services) required for the automation of the service provisioning process such as discovery, adaptation, fault handling, monitoring, mediation, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mashing-up with Google Translator</title>
      <link>/2007/10/mashing-up-google-translator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2007/10/mashing-up-google-translator/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever though about your website or blog to be in multiple languages? Although the language that most people speak is English there might be people who would like to read your web in Russian or Chinese.
Google (as well as some others) provide language tools allowing to translate any text or a website in a particular language to a number of other languages. However, if you want to make your site directly multilingual using these tools, you want to put the translate links directly to your website and customize the translation parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SA-REST: Semantic Annotations for RESTFul Services</title>
      <link>/2007/10/sa-rest-semantic-annotations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2007 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2007/10/sa-rest-semantic-annotations/</guid>
      <description>IEEE Internet Computing magazine in its November/December issue published an article authored by Amit Sheth et al. on SA-REST: Semantically Interoperable and Easier-to-Use Services and Mashups. They discuss how to enable semantic annotations for RESTful services in an analogical way as SAWSDL does. They define a very simple mechanism to mark input, output, lifting, lowering and fault in the REST specification usually available through some XHTML page and by using RDFa and GRDDL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAWSDL: Semantic Annotations for WSDL</title>
      <link>/2007/10/semantic-annotations-wsdl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2007 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>tomas@vitvar.com (Tomas Vitvar)</author>
      <guid>/2007/10/semantic-annotations-wsdl/</guid>
      <description>In November/December, IEEE Internet Computing magazine published our article on the Semantic Annotations for WSDL and XML Schema (SAWSDL). In this article we summarise the results of the W3C SAWSDL Working Group.
SAWSDL is the first step in W3C toward standardising technologies for Semantic Web services. As a standard, SAWSDL provides a common ground for the various ongoing efforts toward SWS frameworks, such as the Web Service Modelling Ontology (WSMO) and the OWL-based Web Service Ontology (OWL-S).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>